# ANTHONY DRANE UX DESIGNER

## **EXPERIENCE**

## City Water Technology // Gordon

UX Consultant, November 2017

Designed a strategy for CWT's website and provided further recommendations to support business development.

• Stakeholder & client interviews, surveys, competitive analysis, business model canvas, affinity mapping, assumptions & hypotheses, ideation, feature prioritisation, sketching, design studios, information architecture, wireframing, usability walkthroughs & presenting.

## **Nine Entertainment Company // Artarmon**

Non-Linear Editor, February 2015-Present

- Designing and editing news packages, features, and overlay to high standards for quick-turnaround on local & national news broadcasts.
- Working collaboratively and independently, solving problems and co-creating stories with journalists and producers.
- Managing people and leading morning shifts; ensuring work is assigned, feasible and published before deadlines.

## Media Exchange Operator, September 2013-January 2015

- Conducted various operational duties around the ingestion, organisation and monitoring of incoming & outgoing media, dealing with complex routing technology in a fast-paced environment.
- Communicated with various department dependents and stakeholders to ensure smooth operation of live broadcasts.

#### 2MCE Regional Community Radio // Bathurst

News Cadet (Journalist & Reporter), June 2012-July 2013

- Independently designed, produced, wrote and presented three live and two pre-recorded community news bulletins daily to Central-West NSW.
- Sourced news, designed rundowns, conducted interviews, wrote stories to format, operated professional hardware & software, and mentored younger cadets.

## The Squawkin' Galah // Bathurst

Documentary Video Editor, August 2013-October 2013

**CSU SeeSeeEye News // Bathurst** 

Multi-media production (various), March 2013-August 2013

**Solutions First // North Sydney** 

Junior IT Technician, December 2009-November 2011

# **EDUCATION**

## General Assembly // 2017

User Experience Design Immersive (UXDi18)

Charles Sturt University // 2011-2013

Bachelor of Communications (Journalism)

#### Self-Directed, Online Learning // 2014-2017

FreeCodeCamp - Front-End Development (2016)

University of Helsinki – Object Oriented Programming P1 (2015) Case Western Reserve University, Coursera – Inspiring Leadership Through Emotional Intelligence (2014)

UC San Diego, Coursera – Learning How to Learn (2014)

## SHORE School // 2009

Australian Tertiary Admissions Rank 92.3

## **PROFILE**

Hey, I'm a Sydney-based UX Designer with a background in Media & Journalism. I believe user-centred, research-backed design is responsible for sustainable business and facilitates social progress. I'm motivated to fail fast, cheap and early, as well as investigate and collaborate with as many stakeholders, users & designers as feasible to get the right design before getting the design right.

## CONTACT

**J** 0428 581 147

■ anthonycharlesdrane@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/anthony-drane

anthonydrane.solutions

# **SKILLS**

Business & Market Analysis
User Research
Research Synthesis
Flows, Scenarios & Concept Maps
Ideation & Collaborative Design
Sketching, Wireframing & Prototyping
Usability Testing
Writing & Presenting
Project & Time Management

# TOOLS

Master: Sketch, Balsamiq || Pen & Paper

|| Velocity ERX, Adobe Premiere

Intermediate: InVision, Anima || HTML, CSS, Javascipt || InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro

**Beginner:** Omnigraffle, Axure || JQuery

# **ACTIVITIES**

- SXSW Conference, Interactive & Film, Texas (2017)
- Mentor to Second-Year Radio Cadets, 2MCE (2013)
- Director of 'Forty,' Winner CSU BATS Wingman Festival's Short Film Competition (2012)
- Volunteer Graphic Designer, Project Futures (2010)

# INTERESTS

- Short Films & Documentaries.
- Philosophy, Psychology & Futurism.
- I play guitar, read excessively, travel, hike & meditate.